Guide to the Reginald Dufour Academic papers, 1979-1994 UA 401
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Reginald Dufour Academic papers
1979-1994
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Dufour, Reginald J.
UA 401
1 Linear Feet 2 boxes
The collection consists of slides used by Dr. Dufour, including published series by NASA, various observatories, and commercial publishers, along with Dufour's slides.
Biographical / Historical
Reginald James Dufour (1948-2020), a Louisiana native, held degrees from LSU and the University of Wisconsin at Madison and was a postdoctoral associate at the Johnson Space Center for two years before joining the Rice University faculty in 1976; he was named Professor Emeritus of Physics and Astronomy in 2016. Dufour played a key role in establishing and equipping the Rice Observatory in 2002. His research specialties included gaseous nebulae and star-forming galaxies, the Hubble Space Telescope, and imagery and spectroscopy observations with ground-based and space-borne telescopes. His numerous publications appeared in the Bulletin and Journal of the American Astronomical Society, The Astrophysical Journal, and Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, among others.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of slides used by Dr. Dufour, including published series by NASA, various observatories, and commercial publishers, along with Dufour's slides.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Index Terms
Subjects
Astronomy; Space sciences; Universities and colleges
Places
United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration
- Series I: Slides
  - Reginald Dufour, Spiral Galaxy, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - James B. Kaler, The Spectra of the Stars, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Kaufmann, Universe (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Michael Zeilik, Astonomy: The Evolving Universe, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - NASA, Hubble Space Telescope, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hubble Space Telescope, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hubble Space Telescope first servicing mission, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - New Lab, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Galaxies (color slides) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Galaxies (black and white slides) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Galaxies (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Planetaries (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - H II Regions (Box 1, Folder 14-16)
  - Diagrams (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Star Fields (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Clusters (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Evolution (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Additional slides (includes NASA missions Mariner, Voyager, Apollo) (Box 2, Folder 5-7)